## KHOA NGUYEN - BEN

## BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE / DATA ANALYST

#### CONTACT

0326294771

bennguyentwfg@gmail.com

in <u>LinkedIn Profile</u>

Ho Chi Minh City, VN

#### SKILLS

Analytical and Problem-Solving skills

Interpersonal / Communication skills

Strategic thinking and Budgeting

SQL / Python / Pyspark / R

BigQuery / Presto / MySQL

Google Sheets / Excel/ Data Studio/ Tableau

#### EDUCATION

Senior Computer Science 2021

**McNeese State University** 

Associate of Science 2018

**Houston Community College** 

### CETIFICATE

# **Google Data Analystics Professional Certificate**

2021

#### **SQL Intermediate Certificate**

2021

#### LANGUAGES

Vietnamese



English

#### PROFILE

ZaloPay

Business Intelligence / Data Analyst with nearly 4 years of experience identifying efficiencies and problems in multiple industries including FnB, Insurance, E-Payment, etc. Google Data Analyst certified with the process-oriented skills to communicate with high-level directors and key accounts stakeholders.

Experienced and driven Marketing Analyst with an impressive background in managing million-dollar budgets while providing analysis and strategy planning. Worked to reduce business expenses and develop logical and advantageous operating plan budgets.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Marketing Strategy Merchant Partnership**

- Leveraging the relationship with merchants to grow ZaloPay paying users pool, visibility/brand awareness through campaign strategies, and trade-off negotiation with Key Accounts Management.
- Working with a team including 5 marketing executives on planning monthly promotion/campaign strategies within controlled budget and in an effective way to compete with competitors and win-win with merchants.
- Manage performance & control 2 million-dollar in 2nd haft budget of a part Online/Offline industries, including:
  - Entertainment ( CGV, Lotte, BHD,...)
  - Retail & FnB (Big C, BHX, Circle K, Highlands, Phúc Long, Con Cung,....)
- Syncing the spending/campaign details with the Finance/Legal team in other to get the approval and reduce to the least of involving in lawsuits and financing statements.
- Analyzing historical data to estimate the growth rate, paying users, GMV, and cost to
  plan the KPI for 2022 with acceptable CPU. Successfully draw the milestone to
  achieve the KPI in 2023 by defining which merchants are suitable for growing on
  users, which is GMV, frequency, etc....forming a clear picture of where to invest
  aligning with the milestone.
- Monitoring closely with Risk team every campaign for any abusive behavior leads to a high loss rate.

### **Business Intelligence Analyst**

ShopeeFood

Aug 2021 - Apr 2022

Apr 2022 - Current

- Manage & maintain CPU by working closely with the marketing team to identify when should be optimized the promotion to users. Research the market, trends, competitors, and opportunity in Tier 2, and 3 cities before investing or expanding the coverage.
- Evaluate the partners' potential, estimate cost should be covered during the onboarding time, rate card, and return feedback to the Merchant Partnership team to deal with merchants.
- Successfully propose the plan to the stakeholders by funneling the traffic of
  users/buyers to understand their bounce rate. Increased the average daily new buyer
  in Feb by 26% and 14% of food buyers on the Shopee app through the exclusive
  voucher plan.
- Analyzing and planning the "Retire/Migrate ShopeeFood App" project by exploring and understanding user behavior to define migrate metrics with the minimum lost rate of both users and GMV.
- Built dashboards to track the Shopee Adoption Rate, MAU/MTU. Created metric to segment "ready to migrate" group of users to forecast the shifting progress which is used to retire the app within this year.

# KHOA NGUYEN - BEN

### BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE / DATA ANALYST

# CONTACT 0326294771 bennguyentwfg@gmail.com Linkedin Ho Chi Minh City, VN SKILLS Analytical and Problem-Solving skills Interpersonal / Communication skills Strategic thinking and Budgeting SQL / Python / Pyspark / R BigQuery / Presto / MySQL Google Sheets / Excel/ Data Studio/ Tableau EDUCATION Senior Computer Science 2021 **McNeese State University** Associate of Science 2018 **Houston Community College** CETIFICATE **Google Data Analystics Professional Certificate** 2021 **SQL Intermediate Certificate** 2021

LANGUAGES

Vietnamese

English

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Data Analyst**

The Woodlands Financial Group

Mar 2019 - Sep 2020

- Working with the Underwriting and Strategy Team to analyze the cancellation/claimed rate. Reduced 12% of the cancellation rate and terminated 50+ contracts on time due to weather by using historical data and predicting the period of tropical cyclones.
- Crawling data from the insurance center into a list to track the "Expired"/"Renewal" group of customers from other companies and their purchase price. In addition, this tracker helps the Strategy team be able to adjust the prices and convert the buyer list to the company's new customer.

## **Freelance Insurance Agent**

National Life Group

Dec 2019 - Sep 2020

Using the database to define customer segmentation. Using cross-sale and
purchase behavior metrics to filter the "ready to buy" group. The result was 150
contracts sold within 3 weeks which was 30% higher than the daily average.
Furthermore, I also expanded the market in the Vietnamese town in Texas from
15 to 37% of customers who purchased a full insurance package